<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Hover Help Text for Really Advanced Setup Mod -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		
		<!-- Start Bonuses +++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_START_BIAS_HELP">
			<Text>
This option allows you to set the start bias for this player.
The game only creates a limited number of starting plots so the actual starting location is not guaranteed.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_GOLD_HELP">
			<Text>Player will start with this amount of Gold.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_GOLD_SLIDER_HELP">
			<Text>Player will start with this amount of Gold. The value can be fine-tuned using the scroll wheel.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_COPY_GOLD_HELP">
			<Text>Copy this starting Gold value to all other players.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_CULTURE_HELP">
			<Text>Player will start with this amount of Culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_CULTURE_SLIDER_HELP">
			<Text>Player will start with this amount of Culture. The value can be fine-tuned using the scroll wheel.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_COPY_CULTURE_HELP">
			<Text>Copy this starting Culture value to all other players.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_FAITH_HELP">
			<Text>
Player will start with this amount of Faith. (Must have Gods & Kings or Brave New World expansion pack.)
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_FAITH_SLIDER_HELP">
			<Text>
Player will start with this amount of Faith. (Must have Gods & Kings or Brave New World expansion pack.)
The game may use all remaining Faith when creating the first prophet.
The value can be fine-tuned using the scroll wheel.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_COPY_FAITH_HELP">
			<Text>Copy this starting Faith value to all other players. (Must have Gods & Kings or Brave New World expansion pack.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_TECH_HELP">
			<Text>Player will start with this number of Free Technologies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_TECH_SLIDER_HELP">
			<Text>Player will start with this number of Free Technologies. The value can be fine-tuned using the scroll wheel.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_COPY_TECH_HELP">
			<Text>Copy this Free Technologies value to all other players.</Text>
		</Row>


		<!-- Terrain +++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_TERRAIN_COUNT_HELP">
			<Text>The number of Terrain plots that will be added by this command (if possible).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_TERRAIN_LAND_WATER_HELP">
			<Text>Water can not be changed to Land and Land can not be changed to Water unless this box is checked.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_TERRAIN_PLACEMENT_HELP">
			<Text>This determines how the mod will search for a suitable tile when placing Terrain.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_TERRAIN_MIN_DISTANCE_HELP">
			<Text>Terrain will be placed at least this far from the player's starting position.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_TERRAIN_MAX_DISTANCE_HELP">
			<Text>Terrain will be placed no further than this distance from the player's starting position.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_TERRAIN_ELEVATION_HELP">
			<Text>Use these buttons to control the elevation when creating Terrain.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_TERRAIN_NO_ELEVATION_HELP">
			<Text>The currently selected Terrain has no elevation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_ADD_TERRAIN_HELP">
			<Text>Adds a Resource command to this list using the current settings.</Text>
		</Row>


		<!-- Features +++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_FEATURE_COUNT_HELP">
			<Text>The number of Features that will be added by this command (if possible).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_REPLACE_FEATURE_HELP">
			<Text>The command will only replace existing features if this box is checked.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_FEATURE_PLACEMENT_HELP">
			<Text>This determines how the mod will search for a suitable tile when placing Features.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_FEATURE_MIN_DISTANCE_HELP">
			<Text>Features will be placed at least this far from the player's starting position.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_FEATURE_MAX_DISTANCE_HELP">
			<Text>Features will be placed no further than this distance from the player's starting position.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_ADD_FEATURE_HELP">
			<Text>Adds a Feature command to this list using the current settings.</Text>
		</Row>


		<!-- Resources +++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_RESOURCE_COUNT_HELP">
			<Text>The number of Resources that will be added by this command (if possible).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_RESOURCE_RELAXED_HELP">
			<Text>
Normally Resource placement is limited by Terrain, Hills, and Features.
If this box is checked then some of these limits will be ignored.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_RESOURCE_PLACEMENT_HELP">
			<Text>This determines how the mod will search for a suitable tile when placing a Resource.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_RESOURCE_MIN_DISTANCE_HELP">
			<Text>Resources will be placed at least this far from the player's starting position.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_RESOURCE_MAX_DISTANCE_HELP">
			<Text>Resources will be placed no further than this distance from the player's starting position.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_RESOURCE_TYPE_HELP">
			<Text>Use these buttons to control what appears in the Resource menu.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_ADD_RESOURCE_HELP">
			<Text>Adds a Resource command to this list using the current settings.</Text>
		</Row>


		<!-- Wonders +++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_WONDER_COUNT_HELP">
			<Text>The number of Natural Wonders that will be added by this command (if possible).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_WONDER_SPRINKLES_HELP">
			<Text>If this box is checked then the command will sprinkle a random number of resources around the Natural Wonder.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_WONDER_PLACEMENT_HELP">
			<Text>This determines how the mod will search for a suitable tile when placing a Natural Wonder.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_WONDER_MIN_DISTANCE_HELP">
			<Text>Natural Wonders will be placed at least this far from the player's starting position.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_WONDER_MAX_DISTANCE_HELP">
			<Text>Natural Wonders will be placed no further than this distance from the player's starting position.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_MAX_COPIES_WONDER_HELP">
			<Text>Click here to go to Map Panel.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_ADD_WONDER_HELP">
			<Text>Adds a Natural Wonder command to this list using the current settings.</Text>
		</Row>


		<!-- Units +++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_UNIT_COUNT_HELP">
			<Text>This number of Units that will be added by this command (if possible).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_UNIT_EXPERIENCE_HELP">
			<Text>Units will be given this amount of experience.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_SHOW_FUTURE_HELP">
			<Text>If this box is checked then Units from eras that are later than the currently selected start era will be shown in the Unit menu.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_SHOW_UNIQUE_HELP">
			<Text>If this box is checked then unique Units that are normally not available for the currently selected civilization will be shown in the Unit menu.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_UNIT_TYPES_HELP">
			<Text>Use these buttons to control what appears in the Unit menu.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_SHOW_NON_COMBAT_HELP">
			<Text>If this box is checked only non combat Units will be shown in the Unit menu.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_SHOW_BOTH_HELP">
			<Text>If this box is checked both combat and non-combat Units will be shown in the Unit menu.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_ADD_UNIT_HELP">
			<Text>Adds a Unit command to this list using the current settings.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- Advanced Setup Panel +++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_RESET_ALL_PANELS_HELP">
			<Text>Set all values in ALL panels to their default values.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_GO_BACK_HELP">
			<Text>Go back to previous screen.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- Civ Panel +++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_AD_AI_HELP">
			<Text>Adds another AI Civilization to the game.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_RESET_CIV_PANEL_HELP">
			<Text>Set all Civilizations options to their default values.</Text>
		</Row>


		<!-- Civ Bonus Panel +++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_EDIT_CIV_NAME_HELP">
			<Text>This opens up the Edit Player Name box which allows you to change this Player's Leader and Civilization names.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_RESET_ALL_CIV_NAME_HELP">
			<Text>
This resets all player name's back to their default value.
This button is disabled when all players are using their default names.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_PREVIOUS_PLAYER_HELP">
			<Text>Moves to the previous player in the player list.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_NEXT_PLAYER_HELP">
			<Text>Moves to the next player in the player list.</Text>
		</Row>


		<!-- Map Bonus Panel +++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_RESET_MAP_BONUS_PANEL_HELP">
			<Text>Set all Map Bonus options to their default values.</Text>
		</Row>


		<!-- Map Panel +++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_CITYSTATES_HELP">
			<Text>
This controls the number of City States that will appear on the map.
This option is not available when Random Map Size is selected.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_VISIBILITY_HELP">
			<Text>
This affects how much of the map is visible to each player when the game starts.
The value indicates the distance in plots from the player's starting position.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_VISIBILITY_MAP_HELP">
			<Text>This causes the whole map to be visible for all players when the game starts.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_DISABLE_ALL_NW_HELP">
			<Text>This disables ALL Natural Wonders in the game.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_DISABLE_OTHER_NW_HELP">
			<Text>This disables all Natural Wonders not created by this mod.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_WONDER_MAX_COPIES_HELP">
			<Text>Use this to set the maximum number of copies allowed for each type of Natural Wonder.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_ACTIVE_CIV_HELP">
			<Text>Only selected Civs will appear in the game.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_RESET_MAP_PANEL_HELP">
			<Text>Set all Map options to their default values.</Text>
		</Row>


		<!-- Game Panel +++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_OPTIONAL_SETTLERS_HELP">
			<Text>
Selecting this option will allow a game to be played where one or more Civs start without settlers.
You achieve this by manually creating the player's starting units in the edit player panel and omitting settlers.
Any player without a starting settler that starts in a isolated position where they have no cities to attack will be given a settler.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_DISABLE_NUKES_HELP">
			<Text>
Selecting this option disables building the Manhattan Project and nuclear weapons.
Nuclear weapons can still be given manually to players by using the player unit panel in this mod.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_RESET_GAME_PANEL_HELP">
			<Text>Set all Game options to their default values.</Text>
		</Row>


		<!-- Misc. +++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_MOD_TITLE_HELP">
			<Text>Really Advanced Setup Mod by General Tso</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_COPY_COMMANDS_HELP">
			<Text>Copy this command list to all other players.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GTAS_CLEAR_COMMANDS_HELP">
			<Text>Remove all commands from this list.</Text>
		</Row>

	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>




