<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 3/16/2013 7:37:21 PM -->
<GameData>
  <!-- TODO: Insert table creation example here. -->
 
  <!-- TODO: Insert table data example here.-->
  
  <!-- Enter your Game Data here. -->
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SM_KAKJAPAN_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Japanese</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SM_KAKJAPAN_DESC">
			<Text>Japanese Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SM_KAKJAPAN_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Japan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SM_KAKJAPAN_DOM">
			<Text>The corridors of power beckon to you, Prime Minister Tanaka. Using every disreputable means available to someone of your former humble status, you have risen through each rank of political power, and now sit at the very top, almost untouched by those not born into guaranteed fortune. Before you stretches the nation of Japan; always present at the edge of every map, however old, and inheritor of a thousand years of history, through which your people refined the arts of pen and sword until they became the envy of this world. And no matter how many typhoons, tsunami, and insane rulers battered the shores of these islands, the Japanese persevered through each and every one.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Prime Minister, your country has at last found its way to the mountaintop, and looks down on a new dawn of prosperity. Can you, at this time of such great opportunity, take the reins of government, taming every mountain and connecting every corner of the land, making sure every village shares each miracle you create? Can you ensure your civilisation stands the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SM_KAKUEI">
			<Text>Tanaka Kakuei</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_SM_SHADOW_SHOGUN_SHORT">
			<Text>The Shogun of Darkness</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_SM_SHADOW_SHOGUN">
			<Text>Improving a tile provides a small [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production boost to its city. May construct one [COLOR_YELLOW]Shinkansen Terminal[ENDCOLOR] building in your empire, which allows airlifting to cities connected to it by Railroad and halves the cost of [ICON_GOLD] Gold buildings in those cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_SM_SHADOW_SHOGUN_NOTIFICATION">
			<Text>Tanaka Kakuei's connections have yielded {1} [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production for {2} as kickback.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SM_LOCKHEED_FIGHTER">
			<Text>Lockheed Fighter</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SM_LOCKHEED_FIGHTER_HELP">
			<Text>An air unit unique to Tanaka Kakuei's Japan. When trained using [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production, a third of the cost of the unit is refunded as [ICON_GOLD] Gold.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SM_LOCKHEED_FIGHTER_NOTIFICATION">
			<Text>Your completed Lockheed Fighter contract provides the treasury with bribes worth {1} [ICON_GOLD] Gold.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SM_KEIRETSU">
			<Text>Keiretsu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SM_KEIRETSU_HELP">
			<Text>A building replacing the Stock Exchange, unique to Tanaka Kakuei's Japan. Has a chance to convert opposing non-enemy military units which end their turn within the city's borders. The chance of conversion depends on the size of the Japanese [ICON_GOLD] treasury.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SM_SHINKANSEN_TERMINAL">
			<Text>Shinkansen Terminal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SM_SHINKANSEN_TERMINAL_HELP">
			<Text>Only one Shinkansen Terminal can be built by Japan, although it has no other requirements.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Cities connected to the Shinkansen Terminal by Railroad can airlift and need only half as much [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production to build [ICON_GOLD] Gold buildings.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SM_SHINKANSEN_BONUS">
			<Text>Shinkansen Station</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SM_SHINKANSEN_BONUS_HELP">
			<Text>This city is connected to a city with a Shinkansen Terminal by rail. It can, therefore, airlift, and build [ICON_GOLD] Gold buildings for half the cost.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_0">
			<Text>Tokyo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_1">
			<Text>Niigata</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_2">
			<Text>Osaka</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_3">
			<Text>Kariwa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_4">
			<Text>Nagoya</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_5">
			<Text>Nagaoka</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_6">
			<Text>Yokohama</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_7">
			<Text>Koide</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_8">
			<Text>Kyoto</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_9">
			<Text>Joetsu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_10">
			<Text>Kobe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_11">
			<Text>Yuzawa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_12">
			<Text>Kitakyushu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_13">
			<Text>Sanjo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_14">
			<Text>Sapporo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_15">
			<Text>Urasa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_16">
			<Text>Kawasaki</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_17">
			<Text>Tsubame</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_18">
			<Text>Fukuoka</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_19">
			<Text>Sekikawa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_20">
			<Text>Sakai</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_21">
			<Text>Murakami</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_22">
			<Text>Sendai</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_23">
			<Text>Kashiwazaki</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_24">
			<Text>Hiroshima</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_25">
			<Text>Ryotsu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_26">
			<Text>Chiba</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_27">
			<Text>Muikamachi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_28">
			<Text>Kumamoto</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_29">
			<Text>Tokamachi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_0">
			<Text>Takeo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_1">
			<Text>Masayoshi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_2">
			<Text>Susumu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_3">
			<Text>Isaji</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_4">
			<Text>Kiichi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_5">
			<Text>Makiko</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_6">
			<Text>Yoshio</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_7">
			<Text>Seisuke</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_8">
			<Text>Hana</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_9">
			<Text>Yasuhiro</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Pedia-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SM_KAKJAPAN_PEDIA">
			<Text>Kakuei Japan Pedia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SM_KAKUEI_PEDIA">
			<Text>Kakuei Text Pedia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SM_KAKUEI_FACT_1">
			<Text>During Tanaka's rise to high office, between the elections of 1946 and 1967, he was implicated in 11 scandals. During the same time, he received nine significant political posts and his voter base in Niigata almost quadrupled.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SM_KAKUEI_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Introduction</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SM_KAKUEI_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Biography</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SM_KAKUEI_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Legacy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SM_KAKUEI_LIVED">
			<Text>1918-1993</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SM_KAKUEI_NAME">
			<Text>Tanaka Kakuei</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SM_KAKUEI_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Japan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SM_KAKUEI_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Japan's postwar leaders have, for the most part, been rather forgettable. The stories of Queen Himiko, Toyotomi Hideyoshi, and Emperor Meiji have given way to a procession of Liberal Democratic Party figures in suits, the sort of people most would have trouble getting the right way round even if they had studied politics. Most of these fungible prime ministers' policy platforms have been forgettable in themselves, too, seen as little more than background noise while the so-called postwar economic miracle busied itself spreading the gospel of the electric rice cooker to each corner of the archipelago.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]There are still, however, a couple of exceptions to this general rule, and the most flamboyant of these concerns a man from Niigata named Tanaka Kakuei, one of the very few postwar PMs without  any form of family background in politics. Widespread corruption is nothing new in the LDP, but uniquely among its leaders, Tanaka positively embraced it, pulling himself out of poverty and right to the top of the country using every disreputable trick possible, and then using similar tactics to do what fit his (arguably peculiar) idea of 'best' for Japan and Niigata. Love him or hate him, this is one postwar PM you can't accuse of being forgettable.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SM_KAKUEI_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Tanaka was the only son of a bankrupt cattle dealer. He dropped out of school at the age of 15 and soon opened his own construction firm, the Tanaka Civil Engineering Company. His business prospered during World War II, largely because of military contracts, and he became one of the richest men in Japan. Entering politics, he was elected to a seat in the lower house of the Diet (parliament) in 1947 and rose rapidly through the ranks of the powerful Liberal Democratic Party to become minister of postal services and communications in 1957. Resigning from that post in 1958, he then served as minister of finance from 1962 to 1964. He became one of his party’s most powerful politicians and was made secretary-general of the party in 1965 and again in 1968.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]After serving as minister of international trade and industry in the cabinet of Satō Eisaku, prime minister from 1964 to 1972, Tanaka succeeded the latter in a surprising upset victory over Satō’s chosen successor, the former foreign minister Fukuda Takeo. Tanaka was a vigorous and popular prime minister; he pushed through many government projects and is sometimes claimed to be responsible for economically revitalizing much of western Japan. He also established diplomatic relations with the People’s Republic of China. Japan’s economic growth slowed and inflation rose during his time in office, however, and in the elections of July 1974 his party made a poor showing. These problems, added to charges that he had profited illegally by means of his office, led to his resignation in December 1974.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Tanaka was arrested in July 1976 and indicted the following month on the charge of having accepted, while prime minister, about $2,000,000 in bribes from the Lockheed Aircraft Corporation in order to influence All Nippon Airways to buy that company’s jet airliners. Despite the political cloud that enveloped him after the indictment, he continued to rule over the largest faction of the Liberal Democratic Party; he thus had a major voice in the selection of three subsequent Japanese prime ministers. After a seven-year trial, Tanaka was convicted in 1983 of bribery and another charge and was sentenced to a fine of 500 million yen and four years in prison. He suffered a serious stroke in 1985, while his conviction was on appeal, and thereafter his power and influence waned.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SM_KAKUEI_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Tanaka was strongly associated with the construction industry, and the late-20th-century LDP doctrine of the doken kokka ('construction state') owes much to his leadership. The doken kokka involves a system in which large proportions of rural economies are propped up by a succession of public works projects guaranteeing permanent construction jobs, complete with all the opportunities for contract profits and LDP vote-gathering that entails. Tanaka's love of large-scale construction is, at its best, what gave Japan the expanded shinkansen network it has today; at its worst, it resulted in the massive concrete scars seemingly blighting half the natural features in the country.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]It is worth noting that Tanaka never lost his popularity in and around his home district in Niigata. Many of his public works projects were focused in the area - including, most infamously, the Joetsu Shinkansen, which almost perfectly skewers the district - and they apparently genuinely did positively contribute to the lives of the local population, to the extent that they kept enthusiastically voting for Tanaka during and after the Lockheed scandal.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SM_KAKUEI_TITLES_1">
			<Text>40th Prime Minister of Japan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SM_KAKUEI_TITLES_2">
			<Text>Representative for Niigata's 3rd district</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SM_LOCKHEED_FIGHTER_TEXT">
			<Text>Lockheed is a US aircraft manufacturer founded in 1926, now part of Lockheed Martin. Although their war planes had something of a distinguished record in the Second World War, the company found itself in financial trouble in the latter half of the twentieth century due to several failed projects and unpopular aircraft. In a somewhat desperate attempt to turn their sales figures around, Lockheed took to bribing several western governments (including West Germany, the Netherlands, and Italy) to award military and civilian aircraft deals to the company, over the course of the 1960s and 1970s.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In the case of Japan, Lockheed had been engaged in bribery for military aircraft deals in the country since at least 1957. However, it was a 1976 scandal, involving millions of yen being paid to Prime Minister Tanaka Kakuei for a civilian contract with All Nippon Airways, that went down in Japanese history. The scandal led to Tanaka getting a prison sentence, but did not end his political career, and the people of the Niigata 3rd district were very quick to forgive him.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SM_LOCKHEED_FIGHTER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Is a set strategy really needed with extra gold?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SM_KEIRETSU_PEDIA">
			<Text>A keiretsu is a Japanese business organisation that acts as a sort of cross between one company and a group of companies. The modern keiretsu system has its roots in the more famous early 20th-century conglomerates known as zaibatsu, which controlled most of Japanese manufacturing between them before the country's surrender in 1945. The US Occupation initially intended to dissolve the zaibatsu, but a shift in strategy from creating a neutral Japan to ensuring Japan helped contain the Soviet Union effectively led to them returning in a new form. Thus, the keiretsu use similar business strategies to the zaibatsu, such as interlocking shareholdings between each of the group's constituent companies. Each keiretsu also incorporates a bank, partly to handle the various flows of money going around the complex network of companies.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Keiretsu tend to have some stake in pretty much every sector of the Japanese economy - there aren't many sectors of manufacturing or finance where Mitsubishi and Sumitomo are nowhere to be found. They also tend to have strong links to other large Japanese companies, which in turn are sometimes referred to as 'vertical keiretsu' for their control of enough of every type of business involved in whatever single sector they do their business in. Both the regular and vertical keiretsu systems are useful to guarantee the sort of medium-term stability that allowed Japan to maintain its lifetime employment system throughout the 'economic miracle' years, albeit not for long after that. Furthermore, much of Japan's increased technological prowess in that time period, and thus the change in the country's reputation overseas which said technology helped to spark, was thanks to the work of keiretsu and keiretsu-affiliated companies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SM_KEIRETSU_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Keiretsu can be a potent weapon against militaristic neighbours in the late game. Sign a few open-border agreements, boost your treasury (perhaps through Lockheed Fighter production and cheap gold buildings in Shinkansen cities), and just wait until your Keiretsu slowly picks off the few units that venture into Japanese territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SM_SHINKANSEN_TERMINAL_PEDIA">
			<Text>The shinkansen (literally, 'new trunk line', or popularly, 'bullet train') was the world's first true high-speed rail network. The first shinkansen line, the Tokaido Shinkansen between Tokyo and Osaka, opened in 1964, in time for the Tokyo Olympics of that year. The futuristic-looking trains running at a then-unthinkable 210 kilometres per hour served as symbols of the new, changed, modern Japan, along with the Olympics itself. Today, the Tokaido Shinkansen operates at 285 kilometres per hour and is still a symbol of 'cool Japan'.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In the years between 1964 and today, however, the shinkansen network has expanded hugely. The 1970s saw grand, ambitious plans for shinkansen lines to every corner of the country unveiled, many of which were subsequently shelved after the debt started piling up. However, many more were subsequently completed: the shinkansen now stretches over the entire length of Honshu and Kyushu, and up to the very south of Hokkaido - along with, of course, Niigata on the Sea of Japan coast, via a line that neatly skewers Tanaka Kakuei's old electoral district. The next level of shinkansen, the Chuo maglev line, is scheduled to open in 2023 at over 500 kilometres per hour, although its status as yet another Tokyo-focused big construction project has drawn some degree of criticism.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SM_SHINKANSEN_TERMINAL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Shinkansen, combined with Japan's other bonuses, encourages a swift form of wide play. Cities can be set up quickly, through airlifting workers and defence units, and subsequently rapidly building infrastructure via the other half of Japan's unique ability. Make sure to build your Terminal on your empire's largest and most significant landmass: if you're on a world map, best not build it on the Japanese archipelago!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Diplo-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SM_KAKUEI_FIRSTGREETING1">
			<Text>Good day. My name is Tanaka, and welcome to Japan. I am sure we have enough to convince you to invest in our growing empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SM_KAKUEI_FIRSTGREETING2">
			<Text>Welcome to Japan. Look around you, and you will see an economic miracle. I am sure that that is enough to make you hope we will be friends.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SM_KAKUEI_DEFEAT1">
			<Text>So it appears as if my actions have, at long last, caught up to me. Well done. Just don't be surprised if your cabinet gets tougher to handle from now on.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SM_KAKUEI_INFLUENTIAL_ON_AI1">
			<Text>Our people are putting concrete on mountains and fantasising about giant monsters. I worry the rest of the world will also succumb to the influence of your culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SM_KAKUEI_INFLUENTIAL_ON_HUMAN1">
			<Text>I see your people are clamouring to connect their hamlets by bullet train. The amazing works of our civilisation are truly inspiring!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Mod Support-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_COLONY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_1">
			<Text>Hakodate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_COLONY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_2">
			<Text>Otaru</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_COLONY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_3">
			<Text>Obihiro</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_COLONY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_4">
			<Text>Wakkanai</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_COLONY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_5">
			<Text>Asahikawa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_COLONY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_6">
			<Text>Kushiro</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_COLONY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_7">
			<Text>Abashiri</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_COLONY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_8">
			<Text>Nemuro</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_COLONY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_9">
			<Text>Noboribetsu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_COLONY_NAME_SM_KAKJAPAN_10">
			<Text>Oshamambe</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>